MARC H. WEINER, CTO/VPE

mhweiner234@gmail.com angel.co/marc-h-weiner linkedin.com/in/mhweiner github.com/mhweiner

With over 16 years of experience, I see ideas come to life by aligning technical and business strategy. I lead cross-functional teams that design and build award-winning applications, driven by research and using an iterative approach. I enjoy problem solving, process and efficiency optimization, team-building, and bringing people together in a collaborative environment.

EXPERIENCE

Ciro, New York, NY Founder, CTO

06/2016 - Current

A simple, UX-centric Agile project management and team collaboration tool, made to help increase communication efficiency and reduce distractions. Fully-responsive, realtime SPA application. Focus on UX, performance, and user-efficiency. (ciroapp.com)

Advizr, New York, NY Director of Front-End Technology, UX 04/2014 - 05/2016

Led the architecture, UX, design, and front-end development of award-winning application from the ground up, with limited resources. (advizr.com)

- Recognized as Best Client Facing Technology of 2015 by FPPad.
- Pre-revenue to over \$2M/yr within 2 years.
- Led and helped build a small team of developers and freelancers. Managed a creative agency, made key hires.
- Transitioned company to an iterative Agile development process, built a flexible custom architecture that helped the company pivot quickly.
- BA/UX/AI, requirement gathering, wire-framing, and prototyping. Solved complex UI problems for financial applications.

Marvel Entertainment, New York, NY Lead Front-End Software Engineer 02/2013 – 10/2013

Contract

Led R&D and architecture of <u>Marvel.com</u>, a high-traffic, content-rich, mobile-friendly consumer-facing website. One of the first such projects to to employ "device agnostic feature-based responsive design" methodology, which is still modern today. Emphasis on strong branding and smooth UX on mobile.

- Led design and development strategy, architecture, meetings, and set standards, methodologies and conventions for a smooth and efficient development process.
- Led in establishing development process to ensure delivery by tight deadline.
- Worked closely with design team to enable them to deliver high quality work within our technical constraints and within deadline, and to prevent roadblocks
- Major technical challenges included R&D, payload size, responsive "high-res" content, performance & optimizations, legacy support, mobile optimization, ad integration, and a tight deadline.

Marc H. Weiner Consulting, New York, NY

Founder, CTO, Lead, APM

01/1999 - 04/01/2014

- Led small cross-functional teams deliver wireframes, designs, and full-stack development of web and mobile applications, under tight budget and deadlines.
- Performed business analysis, requirement gathering, and writing specifications for startups and Fortune 500 companies. Worked directly with clients and stakeholders.
- Worked across medical, industrial, logistics, education, and retail industries.

Remedy Systems, New York, NY

08/2012 - 11/2012

Director of User Experience

Led UX architecture, design and FE-development of cutting-edge medical application. Established Agile development process, PM, scrum, sprint planning, and standards. Mentored junior UX designers and developers.

comiXology (Amazon), New York, NY Senior Front-End Web Developer 11/2011 – 01/2012

Contract

Helped build e-commerce comic bookstore from the ground up with cutting-edge technology for a streamlined shopping and checkout experience. Promoted consistency, best practices, and cross-platform compatibility.

DigitasLBI, New York, NY Front-End Web Developer

10/2005 - 01/2006

Contract

Developed micro-sites for American Express, Delta, The New York Times, and Time Warner.

SKILLS APM, BA, cross-functional team leadership, technical strategy, R&D, UX architecture, UI design, strategic hiring, process design, Agile, SDLC, CI, scalable process & scalable infrastructure, scalable architecture, responsive design, mobile & cross-platform app development, performance optimization, REST API, SPA, TDD, OOP, SOLID, devops, build tooling, automated testing, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP7, Java, C++, python, bash, Cordova, git, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, AWS, GCP & more

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Private Pilot Certificate (SEL) — Federal Aviation Administration, 2015 Computer Science, Aerospace Engineering — University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY, 2005